m 34 -191 l 162 -6 l 25 191 l 129 191 l 213 69 l 359 277 l 360 277 l 465 277 l 265 -6 l 394 -191 l 290 -191 l 213 -81 l 137 -191 l 34 -191
m -32 -191 l -32 191 l 14 191 l 54 134 l 54 -146 l 23 -191 l -32 -191
m -353 191 l -354 4 b -352 -98 -345 -191 -175 -191 l -44 -191 l -44 -124 l -179 -124 b -269 -120 -271 -68 -273 -32 l -44 -32 l -44 35 l -273 35 l -273 191 l -353 191
m 34 -191 l 162 -6 l 25 191 l 129 191 l 213 69 l 359 277 l 360 277 l 465 277 l 265 -6 l 394 -191 l 290 -191 l 213 -81 l 137 -191 l 34 -191
m -32 -191 l -32 191 l 14 191 l 54 134 l 54 -146 l 23 -191 l -32 -191
m -353 191 l -354 4 b -352 -98 -345 -191 -175 -191 l -44 -191 l -44 -124 l -179 -124 b -269 -120 -271 -68 -273 -32 l -44 -32 l -44 35 l -273 35 l -273 191 l -353 191
字　　幕　　侠
ZIMUXIA.CN
关注新浪微博
@FIX字幕侠
原 创 翻 译
中英双语字幕
翻译　独角马　厨师沙拉　芋头
翻译　文生云　希伯来　Jalooyt
校对　多星人　时间轴　iiichiii
后期　Jason肖　特效　小布
监制　多星人
m 34 -191 l 162 -6 l 25 191 l 129 191 l 213 69 l 359 277 l 360 277 l 465 277 l 265 -6 l 394 -191 l 290 -191 l 213 -81 l 137 -191 l 34 -191
m -32 -191 l -32 191 l 14 191 l 54 134 l 54 -146 l 23 -191 l -32 -191
m -353 191 l -354 4 b -352 -98 -345 -191 -175 -191 l -44 -191 l -44 -124 l -179 -124 b -269 -120 -271 -68 -273 -32 l -44 -32 l -44 35 l -273 35 l -273 191 l -353 191
ZIMUXIA.CN
关注新浪微博
@FIX字幕侠
永不者
第一季 第 5 集
对于连环杀手
玛拉黛的公开处刑
国家蒙羞: 正义并非儿戏
艾菲・博伊尔
看看我的大作
我是死亡天师
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
玛拉黛的临终采访
艾菲・博伊尔的独家报道 "上帝惧怕我"
"你们将会对我升入天堂表示震惊 上帝也是"
我们都是上帝的孩子
克拉莎・简・史杜威
受害人姓名
未知
艾菲・博伊尔
绞死她
这不好玩...
...It's not fun...
看着你飞蛾扑火
watching you throw yourself at danger
就好像这是你的宿命
like you think it's gonna propose.
一次次来这里替你包扎伤口
Coming here to patch you up over and over.
这可以很有趣
Could be fun.
我当初被丢在这里 无依无靠
I was left here completely alone
除了从未被真正赋予的任务以外 一无所知
with nothing but a mission I was never actually given,
没有命令 没有目标
no orders, no objectives.
我们帝国之首府停滞不前
The heart of our empire brought to a shuddering halt.
刀已落下 我们要查出手握刀柄之人
The blade is in. We need to know whose hand is on the hilt.
你觉得我和你朋友的死有关
Do you think that I had something to do with your friend's death?
是吗 那真是帮我省时间
Did you? It would save me such a lot of time.
但愿他告诉过你战争时如何处置间谍
I hope he told you what happens to spies during war time.
几天前 还像发现时一样黯淡无光
A few days ago, dark as the day we found it.
而现在...
...And now...
他们说我杀了玛丽
They say I killed Mary.
我从未做过 我只杀天使
I never did it. I only kill angels.
公正 得给她公正的审判
Justice! She gets justice from us!
桃金娘能听懂玛丽的歌
Myrtle understood Mary's song.
她说 "请到下面来找我"
She said, "Come below and find me."
我们需要找的是谁
Who do we need to find?
过了五周...
After five weeks...
精疲力尽地口供取证了五周
five grueling weeks of testimony
关于你十恶不赦且不思悔改的非法行为...
as to your heinous and unrepentant malfeasance...
本庭宣判你已犯下
this court finds you guilty
入室盗窃 偷窃 侵犯人身...
...of the crimes of burglary, theft, assault...
恐吓取财 猥亵 绑架
extortion, indecency, kidnapping,
以及15项谋杀罪
and 15 counts of murder.
你没事了
You're clear.
法院宣判你 玛拉黛
The court therefore sentences you, Maladie,
处以绞刑至死
to be hanged by the neck until you are dead.
处决将于公共广场上执行
Sentence to be carried out in the public square.
愿意观刑之人都可以见证
So that all who wish may see the punishment
对这种邪恶行为的处刑
for such wickedness,
以及你恐怖统治的终结
and the end of your reign of terror.
愿上帝 如果k曾赐予你灵魂
May God, assuming He ever gave you one,
也将之怜悯
have mercy on your soul.
公开处刑
A public execution?
我们30年前就废除了这种杂耍表演
A travesty we abolished 30 years ago.
这是必要的 整个伦敦都在关注
A necessity. All of London is watching.
-全世界都在关注  -没错
- The world is watching. - Yes.
就等着看我们变成野蛮人
As we turn savage.
变成达尔文理论的先祖猿人
Turn into Darwin's ancestral apes.
我的表亲 国王陛下...
My cousin, His Majesty, the king...
真好 谢谢你再次提醒我们你表亲是谁
Oh, yes, please remind us again who your cousin is,
因为我们每天醒来都会忘记
because we wake each dawn having forgot.
我们不是猿人 阁下
We are not apes, Your Grace.
我们在处理一场危机
We are managing a crisis.
身份认证法案 蓝色徽章法案
The Certification Act, the Blue Badge Act.
我们确保附魔人数量可统计 一目了然
We keep the Touched accountable, visible.
-这女人像个牲畜一样被锁着  -她并不痛苦
- The woman is chained like an animal. - She's not in pain,
这是重点
and that's the point.
她能汲取痛苦的力量并逃跑
Pain gives her power she could use to escape.
不能去洗漱或更衣
And not allowed to wash, or change.
这也会让她得到能量吗
Does she gain power from that, hmm?
-还是我们违反了...  -玛拉黛将以她之名受刑
- Or are we violating... - Maladie hangs as Maladie.
她不是什么籍籍无名的罪犯
Not some anonymous prisoner.
这个案子必须让司法得以显现
This is a case where justice must be seen.
有一个合理的担忧
There is a legitimate concern,
这不只是首相的意思
and it's not just the Prime Minister,
这可能会激怒附魔人
about enflaming the Touched.
最糟糕的情况 但风险很小
A minimal risk, at worst.
我已下令军队部署在广场
I have ordered troops deployed around the square,
以及城中任何潜在目标周围
and any potential targets in the city.
但没有大张旗鼓 也没穿着制服 配备军刺
But no marching, dress uniforms, or bayonets.
除宫廷周围外
Well, except around the palace.
女王将照常举行皇家典礼
The queen will have her pageantry.
但不能搞成军事管制
But nothing resembling martial law.
我们得游刃有余地维持秩序 但非孤注一掷
We must keep control, not seem to be grasping for it.
我说的不是乌合之众
I'm not talking about some rabble
向巡警大放厥词
hurling brickbats at patrolmen.
我说的是长远影响
It's the long-term.
我们放出恐怖枪手克鲁斯去杀玛丽・布莱顿
We showed our hand siccing that ghastly gunman Kroos
以表明立场 结果呢
on Mary Brighton, and for what?
一周不到 孤儿院的名册已经翻了一番
Within a week, The Orphanage had doubled its roster.
如果克鲁斯没能让布莱顿闭嘴
If Kroos hadn't silenced Brighton,
这数量可能是十倍
it might've increased tenfold.
而玛拉黛不是什么迷人的歌舞女郎 她是个贱民
And Maladie's not some fetching chorus girl. She's a pariah.
玛拉黛的绞刑将引起一场骚乱 我们都知道
Maladie's hanging will cause a brouhaha, we all know,
-但从长远来看...  -先生们
- but it is in the long-term that... - Gentlemen.
我们发誓要守护帝国
We took a vow to protect the Empire,
杀戮并非儿戏
not to kill for sport.
我们对疾病的起源一无所知
We've learned nothing of the origin of the illness,
或者说... 这桩可怖事件的创造者
or the creator of these... horrors.
你忽略了我关于电力威胁的报告
You ignore my reports on the menace of electricity,
然后当我缺席的时候...
and then when I am absent...
阿尔布雷希特王子 对于您为何缺席
I think, Prince Albrecht, there was some concern
我们心中稍稍存疑
as to the nature of your absence.
关于你对于
About your sympathies
附魔之人的同情心
with regard to the Touched.
尤其是 为何公主在夜深人静时
In particular, why the princess was, uh,
被匆匆送去苏黎世
bundled off to Zurich in the dead of night.
贝蒂娜腰痛症得不行
Bettina has lumbago!
我们愿她能早日康复
And we wish her a speedy recovery.
如你所说 我们的病人是整个帝国
But our patient is, as you say, the Empire.
它需要一次放血疗法
And it requires a bloodletting.
你知道那远远不够
You know that won't be enough.
无法得到长久的安宁
Not for a lasting peace.
-X光  -光谱镜
- X-ray. - Spectralacle.
你用X光扫描了伦敦
You X-rayed London.
这是个光谱...镜
It's a spectral-acle.
因为它可以看穿... 但 没错
Because it can see through the... but, yes.
方框处是我们需要钻孔的地方
The square bits are where we'll need to drill.
其余应该是露天的
The rest should be open air.
直接下去会更容易
Be easier to go straight down.
如果我们想回来 就很难了
Not if we want to come back up.
"加兰蒂"就在大修道院的下方
The Galanthi's right under Grand Abbey,
"灵活杰克"说那里全是打手
and Nimble says it's covered in thugs.
但我们还不知道是哪方势力
But we still don't know whose.
我们会在侦察中知道的
We'll find that out on our reconnaissance.
我研究了各个角度 这是最佳进入点
I've studied the angles, and this is the best place to get in.
那是哪儿
So what's this?
皇家军队
The Royal Military Army.
-这里是更好的吗  -通常情况下不是
- Which is better? - Not usually.
但我们确实有个机会
But we do have an opportunity.
是什么
Which is?
这部分我真不想说
This is the part I don't like so well.
玛拉黛的绞刑吗
Maladie's hanging?
那地方一整天都会很暗
The whole place will be dark for the day.
奥吉学校里的朋友说 所有士兵都派驻出去了
Augie has a friend from school who says everyone's being deployed.
议会大厦 白金汉宫
Grand Parliament. Buckingham Palace.
-他们是在期待一场叛乱吗  -也许
- Are they expecting a rebellion? - Maybe.
你有在策划叛乱吗
Are you planning a rebellion?
一场重逢
A reunion.
-你在害怕  -我没有
- You're afraid. - I'm not.
你害怕见到"加兰蒂"
You're afraid to go see the Galanthi.
是的 当然是
Yes. Yes, of course I am.
至今没有一件事按计划进行 我...
...Nothing's happened the way it should've. I...
如果我... 别这样
What if I... Stop that.
别停 你真是个坏小子
No, don't stop. You're a bad person.
万一这是因为...
.What if that's because...
万一这是因为我呢
What if it's because of me?
如果它看到我是如此糟糕
What if it sees what a horror I've been?
我每晚都在想
I think that every night.
别提凯瑟琳
Don't bring up Katherine.
好吧 这... 这会...
Okay. It's... It's gonna...
这会成功的
It's gonna work, all right?
这一切 会值得的
It's... It's gonna be worth it.
会治愈我们 好吗
It'll heal us. All right?
治愈我们 我们
Heal us. Us.
-治愈这一切  -我不知道 我...
- Heal this. - I, I don't know. I...
-他们在杀女人 但这是种罪  -只是...
- They're murdering women, but this is a sin. - Just...
只是...
Just...
它在孵卵
It's hatching.
与其说孵卵 更像是结蛹
No, uh, more chrysalis than egg.
大致来说
Speaking loosely,
它正在从液态转向... 护目镜
it's moving from a liquid state to... Goggles!
我们正在详细记录这种脉冲
We're keeping exact track of the pulses.
-他们变暗了 但...  -杀了它
- They're dimmer, but... - Kill it.
-什么  -它上面有裂纹
-Ma'am? - It has a crack in it.
杀了它
Kill it!
既然有裂缝 它就能裂开
If it can crack, it can break.
是它自己裂开的 不是我
No, it cracked. I didn't crack it.
我... 现在也做不到
I... and I still can't.
我们的地堡已准备就绪
We have the bunker ready.
再挖个一周 我们就可以铺设轨道了
Another week of digging, and we can lay the tracks.
这东西就会远离城市
This thing will be miles away from the city
-等它显现...  -靠它找治愈方法 这想法还是太幼稚了
- when it emerges... - Our hopes for a cure were childish.
它的能量与日俱增
Its power grows by the day.
现在伦敦又肆虐着一股热潮
There's a fever spreading through London.
你不会忘了吧 明天还有公开处刑
Do you forget we're on the eve of a public execution?
你以为这是巧合吗
You think that's coincidence?
我认为这是正义
I think it's justice.
美国实施绞刑时... 我们会去围观
When we hang someone in America... we watch.
原.. 原谅我
F-forgive me.
玛拉黛杀了许多我的同业翘楚
Maladie killed great men of my profession.
朋友
Friends.
我似乎只潜心于数字 但...
I may seem all numbers, but...
我终究是人
I am still a man.
我依旧会愤怒
I am still capable of rage.
会小肚鸡肠 会怀抱希望
Of pettiness, and hope.
我们俩暴露在这之下的时间比任何人都要长
The two of us have been more exposed down here than anyone,
但你的道德指针并未摇摆
but your moral compass hasn't fluttered.
我依旧有行动能力
I'm still capable.
我们俩也没多生出一对翅膀
Neither of us has sprouted wings.
这个生物并非万能
This creature isn't all-powerful.
如果撒旦就藏于此处
If Satan himself is in there,
他也不是拉维妮娅・毕德罗的对手
I doubt he's a match for Lavinia Bidlow.
我们这是铤而走险
We're taking a terrible risk.
或将毁灭你我
It means to destroy us.
如果我们失去希望...
If we've lost hope...
那说明它已将我们摧毁
it already has.
"这些高高在上睥睨众生之人
"And what of those looking down from above,
伸... 审判这些女人
jud-ging... judging these women
根本不知道等待着自己的审判是何结果
without knowing where their own jud-g-ment ends.
而高居众人之上
When He who sits above all
却未曾轻视众生的k 要求他们承担罪责
and yet looks down on no one calls 'em to account,
他们该如何解释 庆祝杀戮竟是正义之路"
will they explain how celebrating murder was the righteous path?"
她挺有说服力的
She's terribly compelling.
你挺喜欢的啊
Ah, so you liked it?
什么都跟德西雷讲
Telling all to Désirée.
你当然喜欢了 你太好猜了
'Course you did. You are so predictable.
这是特鲁夫人的指令
Hey, it's Mrs. True's orders.
和德西雷聊天 敞开心扉
And talking to Désirée, baring the soul,
除了某些方面 还能缓解压力
among other things, it takes a weight off.
缓解"某些"压力
Among other things.
现在大家都很乐意看到我在这
And now everyone's comfortable with me being here,
除了不能碰银器 小饰品 钱包 纪念品…
except around the silver, and trinkets, purses, keepsakes...
自以为是
Smug.
明天就没这么容易了
Won't be this easy tomorrow.
黑暗洞穴里可没法跳着逃跑
Can't skip away in a dark cave.
我也没这个打算
Oh, I'm not skipping.
很好 我也不想聊这事
Good. I don't want to talk about it either.
走啊 你走 你走了大家都开心
Go on, then. Go. Everybody's glad you're going.
她笑是因为你要走
She smiled because you're going!
男人啊
Men.
我们确实不平等
We truly are the unfairer sex.
"当着公爵和小女孩们的面
"When Maladie is swinging
将玛拉黛绞死
"in the sight of lords and little girls,
这能给伦敦带来和平吗"
will that bring peace to London?"
我觉得"加兰蒂"能带来和平
I guess maybe the Galanthi will.
不管它究竟是啥
Whatever they are.
虽然玛拉黛是赶不上了 但...
Well, not in time for her, but...
能行吗
Is it even gonna work?
绞死玛拉黛
Hanging Maladie.
特鲁夫人说她会因痛苦变得更强 不是吗
Mrs. True said she gets stronger from pain, yeah?
痛苦可以
From pain.
重伤不能 死亡也不能
Not from damage. Not from death.
读最后一段
Read the end.
"绞死玛拉黛不仅是野蛮行径
"Maladie's hanging is more than a barbaric spectacle.
这也让伦敦的灵魂出现裂缝
It is a crack in the soul of the city,
谁知道从中会冒出什么样的毒气
and who knows what venomous vapors will billow from below,
令整座城市感染上最原始 最野性的愤怒
infecting it with the oldest, most animal rage,
让所有人都成为玛拉黛"
and making Maladies of us all."
我可不喜欢这种想法
Well, I don't much like the sound of that idea.
绞死她是没有法律依据的
There's no legal argument for this.
1868年宪法修正案规定 死刑不能公开处刑
Look, the 1868 amendment made executions private,
只有在防止私刑滥用或
only subject to change in order to prevent abuse
赋予其更庄严意义时 才能有所改动
or to give greater solemnity to the act.
公开绞死她是逆法而为 政府也心知肚明
This will do the opposite, and the government knows it.
他们绞死玛拉黛就因为她是附魔之人
They're hanging Maladie for being Touched.
姓名 住址 雇主名
Name, address, employer.
-带佐证书了吗  -带了
- And you've got your letters of support? - Yes.
新来的附魔之人来这儿登记 这里排队
New Touched who are here to register, get in this queue.
-好的  -马上就轮到你了
- Right. - You'll get your turn soon enough.
这个她得随身携带
She wears this everywhere.
如果在公共场合不佩戴 坐牢一个月
If she's seen in public without it, that's jail for a month.
你去那边等着 她去演示间
Now, you wait over there while she's in the demonstration room.
演示
Demonstration?
你们... 想要演示什么
What... what you gonna demonstrate?
就是... 耳朵罢了
It's ju... It's just the ears.
不 我上周在鸡舍里见过这个
Nah, I've seen this one in me henhouse last week.
宝贝 别担心
Aw, don't worry, pet.
我们去把猎犬和马放出来 看你能跑多快
We'll get out the hounds and horses. See how fast you can run.
你一开始四处打听的时候
I told you when you first started
我就跟你说了 博伊尔
nosing around here, Boyle,
-你不能采访她  -就五分钟
- you can't interview her. - Five minutes.
-四分钟她就把你杀了  -三分半
- She'd kill you in four. - Three and a half minutes.
拜托了 蒙迪 我需要采访
Oh, come on, Mundi. I need this.
他们也需要 这些注册手续 都是白费劲
They need this. All this registration nonsense,
不过就是玛拉黛绞刑的温和版本
it's just a milder form of what's going on with Maladie.
玛拉黛...
Maladie...
玛拉黛是伦敦最残暴的杀手
Maladie is the worst killer in London's history.
有关她的消息越少
The less she's heard from,
我们就越有机会控制住这场闹剧
the better chance we've got of controlling this fucking circus.
你也不想看她被绞死
You don't want this hanging either.
不 我想要秩序
No, I want order.
我想要恶人受罚 好人受保护
I want the wicked punished and the good protected.
那就行动起来 别干坐在桌子前
Then do something besides sitting at your desk
就盯着那些附魔女性
ogling the Touched women.
我不能见附魔女性
I can't see the Touched women,
你也不能见玛拉黛
and you can't see Maladie,
这只能帮你增加报纸销量
'cause it helps nothing except your sales.
销量太重要了
My sales matter.
只有我能展现附魔人的人性光辉
I'm the only one showing the human side of the Touched.
蒙迪 报纸可以胡编乱造
Mundi, people can print whatever they want.
但我还是希望展现真相
I am still in favor of the truth.
-这是谁  -凶杀案
- Who's this? - Murder.
铁路工人想让玛拉黛背黑锅
Railmen tried to throw it on Maladie's pile.
没有身份证明 也没人上报失踪 恰是她的一贯作风
With no ID, no one missing, it fits the description.
他们可没有认真模仿字迹
Well, they didn't put much effort into matching the writing.
我有这件外套
I have that coat.
或者说同风格的
Or that style.
工作女性流行穿这种
It's popular with working women.
剪裁干练 价格便宜
It's a sharp cut, and it's cheap.
我猜她是坐办公室的
I'll wager she worked in an office
但是经常出外勤
but was out a lot of the time.
她当时在地下 市议会附近
She was in the underground, city council,
是秘书 还是说那样的"秘书"呢
a secretary, or a... "secretary."
你查出她的身份 我就带你去见玛拉黛
You put a name on her, I'll take you to Maladie myself.
认真的吗
You mean it?
假的
I do not.
毕竟 两只鸵鸟都是雌性
After all that, both the ostriches were females.
-拉维妮娅 你还好吗  -没事
- Lavinia, are you all right? - Oh, it's nothing.
眼睛有点痛
Slight ache behind the eyes.
这件西服背心是你自己买的吗
Did you buy that waistcoat on your own?
像是斯旺的衣服
It looks like one of Swann's.
不是… 我只是… 换换花样
No, I just... I just thought... Hello.
你以后还是离他远点
You need to steer clear of him in future,
现在他那恶心的俱乐部
and now that that ghastly club of his
竟还完成了登记备案
has become a matter of public record.
他是我的朋友
He's my friend.
也是你的朋友
He was your friend, as well.
你还… 还记得那次你带我们去溜冰吗
Do you... Do you remember when you took us ice skating with you?
他假装自己是冰上舞者
He made you laugh all day
逗你笑了一整天
just pretending to be an ice dancer.
记得 他十岁的时候是很可爱
Yes, he was charming at 10.
奥吉 恶魔往往表现得很讨人喜欢
Augie, the devil may take a pleasing form,
你又容易轻信别人 我认为…
but you trust people, and I think...
我…
I...
头痛的事你还是得告诉沃特森医生
You know, you must call Dr. Waterson about those headaches.
或者我去告诉雨果 你觉得他看着讨人喜欢
Or I'll tell Hugo that you think he has a pleasing form,
那你的头疼可没完没了了
then you'll never hear the end of it.
-千万别  -就应该绞死她
- Stop it. - They should hang her,
然后开枪打她
and shoot her.
确保万无一失
Just to make sure.
我们要提前多久去
How early are we going?
我们能叫个跑腿小子占前排吗
Can we pay a boy to hold a place in front?
你们他妈不如把枪带上 自己开枪啊
Why don't they just bring guns and shoot her themselves?
我们不是谋杀犯 女士
We are not murderers, madam.
当然不是 你们只是想看热闹
No, you just like to watch.
最起码玛拉黛还挺有职业精神
At least Maladie has a work ethic.
你在说什么
What are you saying?
-没什… 没什么…  -不要替我道歉
- Oh, noth... noth... - Don't apologize for me.
你哪来的胆子
How dare you?
我不是什么疯疯癫癫的妈
I'm not someone's dotty mother.
到处都有趁火打劫的人
There are vultures everywhere.
华冠丽服 一幅道貌岸然的样子
Dressed up in hats and fine silks.
是的 我曾经很擅长溜冰
Yes, I was quite good at skating.
比我们其他人都强上一大截
Rings around the rest of us.
你看 我一直是不起眼的那个
You know, that, that's something that hasn't changed.
你明天不许待在城里 奥吉
You're not to be in the city at all tomorrow, Augie.
-没得商量  -没有 当然了…
- Don't argue. - No, no, of course, no. I, um...
我明天要去布莱顿
I'm going to Brighton for the day.
谢谢
Uh, thank you.
有个建筑的揭幕式…
Um, a... a building's opened up
或许是一个… 不错的鸟类保护区
that might make a... A good new bird sanctuary.
最近大众对这些很有兴趣
There's been a lot of interest from the public of late.
没错 人类对同类越是残暴
Yes, the more barbaric we humans are to each other,
对宠物就越是精心呵护
the more we pamper our pets.
或许是越需要宠物的陪伴呢
Or maybe the more we need them.
奥吉…
Augie...
明天记得从布莱顿给我带点有趣的东西回来
Bring your sister something fun back from Brighton.
当然了
Of course.
有个守卫说玛拉黛唱歌了
One of the guards did say Maladie sings.
-童谣儿歌那种  -可真是明察秋毫
- Nursery rhymes and such. - How insightful.
好吧 只是
Well, it's just, you know,
这都跟心灵能力有关 真的
it's all about mental capacity, really.
你他妈在玩我吗
Are you fucking playing with me?
他要起诉我 都他妈疯了
He's pressing charges. This is insane!
汉弗莱斯勋爵严重烧伤
Lord Humphries was badly burned.
伯蒂・亨弗里斯是个恶霸 是个懦夫
Bertie Humphries is a bully and a coward,
他没被烧伤 他被冻伤了
and he wasn't burned, he was frozen.
他为什么会被冻伤 是他没长耳朵
And he was frozen because he will not hear the words,
我和他说了"不要碰"
"Don't touch!"
罗纳德是个很棒的艺人
Ronald is a great act.
他能冰镇你的饮料 你能看到自己呼出的气
He can chill your drinks. You can see your breath,
-但你伸手去抓 只会…  -罗纳德没有登记在册
- but you grab it, you're only going to... - Ronald isn't registered.
一个未注册的附魔者不配争辩抱怨
An unregistered Touched can't contest a complaint.
如果勋爵穷追不舍
If his lordship pursues this,
-你会…  -伤害豁免书
- you will... - Injury waiver.
有这张纸 你才能申请摆渡人会员资格
You cannot apply for membership to the Ferryman's without it.
伯蒂真的想把这件事公之于众吗
Does Bertie really want to go public?
要是能和亨弗里斯夫人说上话 我不甚荣幸…
Because I am more than happy to speak to Lady Humphries...
敲诈勒索是违法的
Extortion is still illegal.
这不是敲诈勒索 我只是愤怒
This is not extortion. It is umbrage.
老天啊 你知道我有多辛苦吗
Oh, God. Do you know how hard I am working?
处理琐碎的法律问题
Dealing with petty legalities
还有折磨人的书面文件
and excruciating paperwork,
现在还有个蠢货在浪费我的时间
and now some idiot is wasting my time
只是因为他对附魔者充满愤怒
because he's got angry with the Touched.
混蛋 你当然能懂
Bugger. Of course you do.
命运是多么奇妙
What a strange fate.
我们都成了坐办公室的
We've become men with offices.
看着你就好像在照镜子
It's like looking in a mirror.
我要怎么摆平这件事
How do I make this go away?
你觉得我的艺人想上政府黑名单吗
Do you think my acts want to be on a government list?
附魔者知道人们的看法
They know how people feel about them,
即使是渴望他们的人
even people who desire them.
尤其是渴望他们的人
Especially people who desire them.
每种“转变”都是独特的
A "turn" is unique.
它是你身上的烙印 就像…萨尔金特的肖像画
It marks you, like a... Like a Sargent portrait.
[美国画家 多为上层人士作肖像画]
那叫什么来着 指纹
Or, um, oh, God, what's that thing? Fingerprints!
没有完全相同的两枚指纹 真是不敢相信
Are really no two alike? That seems mad.
我们要把你的人登记起来
We have to register your man.
我不会写上他们的工作场所
I won't list his place of employment,
但你要让亨弗里斯勋爵满意
but you need to give satisfaction to Lord Humphries,
而不是威胁他
not threats.
给他送匹马
Send him a fucking horse,
随便什么有钱人的东西 别再惹麻烦了
or whatever you rich people do, and no more of these.
如果你不能保护好你的人
If you can't keep your people safe,
你就给我关门歇业
I will shut you down.
你不是什么坐办公室的
You ain't a man with an office.
你只是个耍花招拉皮条的 还在玩火
You're a pimp with a gimmick, and you're playing with fire.
-再说一遍 不是烧…  -那是一条活生生的命
- Again, it wasn't fire... - It was someone's life!
我不知道你为什么总是…
I don't know how you always...
明天 我们要杀一个女人
Tomorrow, we are going to kill a woman
就为了娱乐大众
for the public's entertainment.
这就是现在的伦敦 它…
'Cause that's what London is now. It is...
所有人全他妈变成了开膛手杰克
Jack the fucking Ripper grown into an 'ole city.
这么喜欢娱乐活动 你应该来看看
You're in entertainment. You should come.
沾染泥土 嗅着鲜血
Get in the dirt, smell the blood.
你就会知道你到底要对什么负责了
Then you'll know what's on your hands.
弗兰克 为什么你要做一份你痛恨的工作
Frank, why did you take a job you hate?
因为我和爱这份工作的人一起
'Cause I work with the people who love it.
-打扰一下  -我确实了解一点…
- Oh. Excuse me. - Do know a bit about your...
你把耳朵贴在门上听了吗
Had your ear to the door, I hope?
没这个必要
Oh, I didn't need to.
你是雨果・斯旺
You're Hugo Swann.
我写附魔者的故事
You don't write about the Touched
自然也听说了伦敦最恶名昭著的经理
and not hear about London's most infamous impresario.
这我可不会承认
I deny everything.
我不… 不想打听你的事
Oh, I'm not... I'm not after your story.
但你在四处打探某些事
But you are after something.
那事连你都不知道
Something you can't get me.
你是在挑战我吗
So it's a challenge, is it?
你喜欢这样
You'd like that.
我更希望吃着普吉尼餐馆的牡蛎慢慢聊
I'd like it more over a plate of oysters at Pegini's.
大家都是大忙人 没空花一个下午
We're both much too busy to spend the afternoon
搞清楚到底是谁利用谁
seeing who gets to use who,
但你能为我做一件事
but there is something you can do for me.
-奥吉  -怎么了
- Augie? - Yes?
你是那只乌鸦吗
Were you a crow?
-你说什么  -那边那只鸟 你是通过它偷窥我吗
- What? - Up there, were you peering at me by way of bird?
老天… 没有啊
Oh! Oh, G... No, good God, no-no.
不是的 我…我是我自己
No, no, I... I was... I was me.
我… 就在自己身上
I was me, in, in... in me.
我不是… 我是为了那个会议来的
I don't... I don't mean... I came, I came for the meeting.
-我不会… 永远不会  -你不会吗
- So I would... I would never! - Wouldn't you?
-那只鸟特别怪异地盯着我洗澡  -这…
- That bird seemed awful keen on my ablutions. - Well, I...
这只是…
I mean, it's...
这只是…一只鸟
It's a... It's a bird.
我都不知道你在洗澡
I-I didn't even know you were bathing,
不过那是只 是只红翼歌鸫
and that-that-that that was a redwing, anyway.
它们从来就不听话
They never listen to a word, I think.
这次我又被录音了吗
Am I being recorded again?
当然没有
Of course not.
我进来的时候应该大点声的
I s-should make more noise when I come in.
没事 就是...这一切太疯狂了
No, it's just, um... the madness of all this.
仿佛恶之花在绽放
It's as though sin is in bloom.
人们不是越俎代庖 就是袖手旁观
People doing what they oughtn't, or doing nothing.
就好像在考验我们
It's like we're being tested,
像是那种考试结束
but it's that dream where the test's over,
可你连笔都没找到的噩梦
and you've not found your pencils.
但你不会骗我的 对吗
But you're telling me the truth?
我绝不会辜负你的信任
I would never betray your trust.
该留给丈夫看的 你一眼都不会偷看
Wouldn't sneak a quick glance at what a husband's meant to see?
-绝对不会  -我的裸体就那么让人提不起兴趣吗
- Never. - Well, is my naked frame a source of dullness then?
-打扰你们了吗  -没关系 请说
- Am I interrupting? - Yes, please!
我已经把钻孔机弄好了 我操作给你看
I've got the drill all ready. Let me show you.
奥吉 观鸟还顺利吗
Augie, how's the bird watching?
-我...  -准备好明天让它们放声高歌了吗
- I... - You ready to make them sing tomorrow?
噢 当然 当然
Oh. Oh, yes, yes.
他们会发出各种各样的声音
They'll make all sorts of noise.
它们会猛扑下来 我训练了很久
They'll swoop about. I've been practicing.
绝对能完美地分散钻孔吸引到的注意力
Be the perfect distraction for the drilling.
你
What do you, um,
你觉得会在下面找到什么
what do you think you'll find down there?
如果我能问的话
If-if-if it's all right for me to ask.
我不确定我... 在什么位置...
I'm not sure what I'm... What level of...
我知道是"加兰蒂" 而且是单数
I-I know it's Galanthi, uh, even in the singular.
爆炸螺栓上的定时器之前总出问题 但现在...
The timing on the explosive bolts was the issue, but now...
我们会找到答案的
We'll find answers.
是否安全 下面还有谁
Is it safe, who's down there with it?
从那些人身边把它带走需要做什么
What do we need to get it away from them?
各种各样的问题 但就说是"希望"吧
There's more, but can I just say hope?
那就足够了
You could have only said that.
当到达合适深度时 只需要...
And when you reach the proper depth, you just...
那...那层应该是...
Uh, that... That'd be the floor that it...
收不回来了
Yeah, that's not coming back.
回不来了吗
No?
动作麻利点儿
Keep it movin'.
玛拉黛明天就要被绞死了
Maladie hangs tomorrow.
别太心急 豆芽菜们
You mustn't rush, my sprouts.
如果不能挂起来 那就不是绞死了
It ain't a hangin' if she don't swing.
动起来 动起来
Chop chop!
把他带到后面去
Bring him 'round the back.
一定要有条不紊
Slow and steady.
还有一晚上呢 不着急
You's got all night.
吉尔伯特・马森
Gilbert Massen.
业界巨头 上议院贵族
Captain of industry, Peer of the Realm.
我是不是得称呼你一声"勋爵"
Am I meant to call you "lord"?
难道我得叫你"国王殿下"吗
Am I meant to call you "king"?
这座机器真是令人惊叹
This machine's impressive.
是派南斯・阿代尔的杰作吧
Penance Adair's work, I think.
没错 很有意思
Yeah. It's fun.
我让孩子们在院子里开着玩
I let the kids tool about the yard in it.
但并不是很实用
Not very practical, though.
如果出事故 我还是喜欢壮硕的马儿
If I ever crash, I like a nice fat horse
能在前面给我挡一挡
in front of me to take the brunt.
你他妈想要啥
What the fuck do you want?
我想要伦敦尽在掌控
I want London under control.
-意思是受你掌控  -意思是不要让怪物当道
- Meaning yours. - Meaning not overrun by monsters.
怪物吗 玛拉黛明天就被绞死了
Monsters, yeah? Well, Maladie stretches tomorrow.
与此同时 篝火安妮可以随意放火烧了我们的财物
While Bonfire Annie is free to set fire to both our holdings,
而一个没受过教育的爱尔兰女孩
while an uneducated Irish girl
能在几天时间里建造出这玩意
builds something in days that men of industry
而行家花了几年时间还一事无成
have labored over for years.
威胁到自然秩序的东西
A thing that threatens the natural order
即使再美丽 那也是可怕的
is by definition monstrous, even if it's pretty.
自然本就无秩序可研 吉利
There's nothing natural about order, Gilly.
其中有混乱 有野蛮
There's chaos. Savagery.
有像我们这样的人
And then there's men like us,
创造出足够的秩序
who carve out just enough order
让我们变得不可或缺
to make ourselves absolutely necessary.
你来找我不是因为
You didn't come here
你害怕外面那些漂亮女士
'cause you're afraid of the pretty ladies.
反正你会派丑八怪去杀死她们
You just get ugly men to murder 'em.
不是吗 奥迪恩
Isn't that right, Odium?
奥迪恩曾被派去杀死阿玛莉亚・特鲁
My man Odium was sent to kill Amalia True.
他以为是我下的命令
Thought it was an order sent down from me,
法院也乐意看到这种结果
which the law would've happily confirmed.
现在你看着我的眼睛 凭良心讲
Now you look me in the eye, hand on heart,
告诉我这个男人并不丑陋
and you tell me that this man is not ugly.
我看到的只有一名战士
I see only a soldier
被体重不到他的五分之一的女人放倒了
who was laid out by a woman one-fifth his fighting weight.
我们有共同的敌人
We have a common enemy.
某个人 某个组织
Someone, some group,
正想重写社会规则
is rewriting the rules of reality.
如果我们不想法子制止...
If we don't find a way to control it...
你知道为什么他们叫我乞丐王吗
You know why they call me the Beggar King?
因为我一无所有
Hmm? 'Cause I had fuck-all,
但依然有人追随我
and men followed me anyway.
附魔之人会改变这个社会
The Touched are gonna change things.
那该死的长弓也是 我能够适应
So did the fucking longbow. I'll adapt.
我不是在寻找同盟 奥林先生
I'm not looking for an ally, Mr. Orrun.
我有份差事 薪水绝对让你满意
I have a job. It pays obscenely well.
这不就好说了
Now was that so fuckin' hard to say?
我们找遍了这件事的起因 想寻找治愈方法
We have looked for the source of all this, for a cure.
我们采取了一些措施...
We've taken steps to...
但我们只在幕后操纵 该出手时才出手
But we're behind, reacting when we should act.
但玛拉黛的绞刑给了我们一个改变这种局面的机会
Maladie's hanging presents an opportunity to change that.
准备好
To be ready.
准备好 你是说她可能会冒险越狱
Be ready? You expecting some kind of daring escape?
不 绞死玛拉黛 是正义的举措
No, Maladie hangs. Justice will be seen.
虽然她的死会平息众怒
But in the short run, it will stir up emotions
但短期内也会引起不小的情绪波动
as much as it placates.
附魔人 纯化论者
The Touched, the Purists,
他们的不满已经到达顶端
their defiance is at a fever pitch.
没错 你想让我的人维护社会治安
Right, and you want my men to keep the peace.
维持自然秩序
Maintain the natural order, as it were?
我们这边的想法 是的
As far as my people know, yes.
但是 对我来说很明显的一点是
But, uh, it's become apparent to me
如果要让伦敦于祸乱中幸免
that if London is going to be saved from chaos,
那必须要先出现祸乱
it needs to see chaos.
我需要你制造祸乱 但适可而止
What I want from you is just enough.
-你要上楼去吗  -我得重新捣鼓一下钻孔机
- Are you heading up? - I have to finish rebuilding the drill.
-姑娘们怎么样  -有点紧张
- How are the girls? - Mmm, a bit jittery.
除了桃金娘 她因为不能去正生气呢
Except for Myrtle, who's angry she doesn't get to go.
她应该就是为这事生气
I'm pretty sure that's what she was angry about.
她还得继续上她的写作课
She has to get on with her writin' lessons.
如果确定安全的话 我会带她去的
I would take her if I knew it was safe.
她知道"加兰蒂"在说啥
She speaks Galanthi.
有几个姑娘说是你杀了露西
A couple of the girls were saying you killed Lucy.
安妮让她们闭嘴 但她本身就挺吓人的
Annie shut them down, but she's a bit frightening herself.
但你知道我没有
But you know I didn't.
当然 你永远不会这么做
Oh, of course not. No, you would never.
不 我会
No, I would.
我有这个打算 所以你才知道我没有
I wanted to. That's how you know I didn't.
当然 我也很想念露西
And yes, I miss Lucy, too.
玛丽应该不会想念她
I wonder if Mary does.
-不 我不是说...  -他们不站在我们这边 就是...
- No, I'm not saying that... - They're either with us, or...
为什么不试着原谅呢
Well, what about forgiveness?
这个世界依然存在宽恕 对吗
I mean, forgiveness still exists in the world, doesn't it?
或者说 我们能否找到解药
Or did we come up with a cure?
让善意一同萌芽
Was kindness just germs all along?
明天这个时候我保证你就不用再担心了
This time tomorrow, I promise you won't be worried.
只是 我总是...
It's just, I always...
我一直说我不会制作武器
I always say that I won't make weapons.
但我的大部分的发明
But most of my gimcracks,
如果使用不当的话 真的会取人性命
they could kill someone in the wrong circumstances.
一个烛台 一桶水 都有可能
So could a candlestick. A pail of water.
我的机器 他们蕴藏暴力
They're violent things, my engines.
有时候能量本身 好像就... 冷酷无情
Sometimes energy itself, it just seems... relentless.
派南斯 "加兰蒂"会理解你的...
Penance, the Galanthi will know your heart...
像我一样...
the way I know...
我得把钻孔机修好
I need to finish the drill.
? 不在意玫瑰 ?
? Unmindful of the roses ?
[维多利亚女诗人克里斯蒂娜・乔治娜・罗塞蒂的"海边孤坟"]
? 也不在意荆棘 ?
? Unmindful of the thorn ?
? 收割者已经疲累 ?
? A reaper, tired, reposes ?
? 沉睡于谷堆之上 ?
? Among his gathered corn ?
? 我将会... ?
? So might I... ?
? 在破晓之前 ?
? Till morn' ?
? 如岁末的十二月般寒冷 ?
? Cold as the cold Decembers ?
? 像过往那样沉寂 ?
? Past as the days that set ?
? 唯有一人尚未忘却 ?
? Whilst only one remembers ?
? 其余人全都忘记 ?
? And all the rest forget ?
? 但有一人铭记心底 ?
? But one remembers yet ?
-昨晚睡得咋样  -双腿一站 两眼一睁
- How did you sleep? - Standing up, with my eyes open.
工作一晚 我压根没睡
And working. I didn't sleep.
-这些是啥  -我们要这么做
- What am I seeing? - This is how we do it.
做...什么
How we do... what?
把玛拉黛救出来
This is how we save Maladie.
我知道"加兰蒂"是希望的关键
I know the Galanthi is the key to our hopes,
我们需要尽快行动 但是...
and it needs us to come for it as soon as we can, but...
玛拉黛今天就要被公开处刑了
But Maladie is going to be murdered this day out in public,
但我不能坐视不管 我做不到
and I can't let it happen. I know I'm not meant to.
我已经目睹过附魔人的死亡
I've seen it done once,
如果我有能力阻止这件事
and if I have the power to stop it,
那么这就是我拥有能力的原因
then that is the reason I have power at all.
玛拉黛不是玛丽
Maladie is not Mary.
她想杀了玛丽 还有你
She tried to kill Mary, and you.
-我不是说她...  -她在大庭广众之下
- I'm not saying she... - She murdered a dozen people,
杀了几十号人 还记得吗
also in public. Remember that?
这是对真实威胁的合法处决
This is the legal execution of a genuine threat
-何况她非常不快乐  -所以这还是她的福祉
- who is also violently unhappy. - So it's a mercy killin'.
有时候 确实是
Sometimes it's a mercy.
但这次不是 这是私刑
But this time it's a lynching.
是他们吹嘘的资本 是在杀鸡儆猴
For them to crow at, and for us to expect.
唇亡齿寒 接下来就是无休止的杀戮
It's a noose in a row of nooses next to a row of nooses.
你是要我背弃
You expect me to turn my back on the only power
一个月前就召唤我的
that can make all of this right
能将一切拨乱反正的唯一力量
that told me a month ago it needs me
反而让我去向民众证明
so that we can prove to the public
我们和那个疯子杀手是一伙的 是吗
we're all in league with a psychotic killer?
那么... 那才是自寻死路
How is that... That's all the nooses.
这样附魔之人会置身危险中
That's putting the Touched at risk
这远远不如让大众去...
much more than letting a crowd foam over one...
我知道你不会同意 特鲁
I know you're not comin', True.
虽然你来会好一点 不过..
I'd feel better if you did, but...
我不会让你这么做的
I can't let you do it.
-我们非要闹到这个地步吗  -如果你受伤了
- Oh, let's please not go down that road. - If you get hurt,
-况且你肯定会受伤...  -当然 我知道
- and you will get hurt... - Oh, yes, 'cause I know,
我就是个小屁孩 没经历过战争
I'm a child. I've not been in battle.
我没生吞活剥过穷凶极恶的敌人
I've not killed and eaten a dozen fierce men.
我也... 没有
I also haven't.
但我身在这个世界上
But I am in the world.
上帝创造这个世界 我身在其中
I am a part of God's world.
我相信k不想看到人类倒退
And I don't believe He means for us to go backwards,
铲除异类 就为了取乐
killin' each other for sport.
我们明天可以去救人 救孩子
We'll go save a dozen people tomorrow. Children.
那不是重点
That's not the point.
救小猫咪呢
Kittens?
救玛拉黛 就是现在
It's her. It's now.
我体内像是有什么破碎了
Something inside me broke.
就像是断了肋骨 特鲁 那很疼
It, it, it snapped like a rib, True, and it hurts.
我不能无视预兆 苟活在此
I will not live with the thought that I ignored that s-sign.
所以是上帝让你去救玛拉黛吗
So God is telling you to save Maladie.
不 k叫你放弃她了吗
No. Is He telling you to abandon her?
你的"加兰蒂"会熟视无睹吗
Would your Galanthi look kindly on that?
或许它能治愈萨拉呢
And could it not heal Sarah?
帮她回到从前的样子
Make her who she was before?
你... 你真的没有想过吗
Have you... have you never even wondered on that?
不是所有的事都可以回到从前
There are things you can't come back from.
那只是你因不敢尝试而提出的苍白理论
That's a theory you're awful anxious not to test.
这就要扯回我对萨拉所做的事了
So this is about what I did to Sarah.
这是为了那些女孩
It's about the girls.
他们所有人 在这里和在外面的
All of them, in here and all out there.
不仅是他们的安全
Not just their safety.
而是他们如何看待这个世界
It's about how they see the world.
当这个世界变得癫狂时
A part of them breaks or goes quiet for always
而我们却坐视不管
when the world turns beastly.
有的人会崩溃 或永远沉默
When we just let it.
你不能带她来这儿
You're not bringing her here.
我是说 在你穿过枪林弹雨救她出来
I mean, after many, many people shoot you,
她还因为好玩背后捅你一刀后
and Maladie stabs you because it's funny,
她半只脚也不能踏入这里
she doesn't set a foot in this place.
我说了我有计划
I said I had a plan.
特鲁 我知道几天后
Look, True, I know it'll be harder
守卫人员增多 下去会变得困难
in a few days with more people around,
-但"加兰蒂"仍然...  -不 我... 你什么意思
- but the Galanthi is still... - No, I'm... what?
我要去 就今天
I'm going. Today.
我要去
I'm going.
我带上钻子 呼吸阀 你能做的都做了
I've got my drill, my breathers. You've done your part.
不好意思 你的计划还没到这步吗
I'm sorry, did your plan not get as far as this?
你没看出我的潜能吗
Did you not see my potential energy
有能力完成这该死的任务
potentially doing the fucking job?
-不...  -我他妈才不要因为你什么肋骨疼痛
- But... - I'm not turning my back on the Galanthi
就背叛"加兰蒂"
because you got a fucking pain the ribs.
因为世界的未来取决于我在做的事
The future of the world depends on what I'm doing.
世界的未来取决于眼下
The future of the world depends on the present.
这不就是你在这里的原因吗
Isn't that why you're here?
我不知道我为什么在这
I don't know why I'm here.
我不知道事情何以至此 也不知道接下来做什么
I don't know how it got this far or what I'm doing next.
我只知道我不会做什么
I know what I'm not doing.
我不会将自己的痛苦错认为想法
I'm not mistaking my pain for an idea.
看看还有多少人听我指令吧
So let's see who still thinks I should lead.
好了 各位 集合
All right, everybody, gather around,
尽管你们已经集合好了
since you already have.
如果刚才有人没偷听
If you weren't listening in,
阿代尔小姐和我之间出现了一些分歧
Miss Adair and I have come to a bit of a crossroads.
我会在几分钟后出发
I am leaving in a few minutes
寻找"加兰蒂" 按计划行事
to find the Galanthi, as we've planned.
我知道一直没搞清楚"加兰蒂"是什么
I know I've been vague about what that means,
但我们第一步就该了解
but it's the first step to learning
为何我们被聚集于此
why we were brought here together,
以及接下来我们该如何行动
and what we're meant to do next.
然后我去玛拉黛去救...
And I'm going to Maladie to save...
我要到广场阻止这场绞刑
I'm going to the square to stop that hanging.
我要救玛拉黛
I'm going to save Maladie.
很疯狂 是吧
That's mad, right?
仿佛她仍是上帝的孩子 我们都是
Acting like she's still a child of God. Well, we all are.
无论表现得多么残暴 我们都拥有灵魂
We all have a soul, no matter what viciousness people are spewing.
我要把玛拉黛从他们偏执的魔爪中解救出来
I am going to pluck Maladie right from out their bigoted claws,
让世界知道附魔者不是大庭广众下任人鱼肉的
and let the world see that the Touched are not here to be slaughtered for show.
这段话我练了好几遍 但还是紧张到出汗
I have practiced saying this, and I feel sweaty!
好了
All right.
本来是一个计划 现在变成两个了
We had a plan. Now there are two.
我不会强迫任何人和我一起
I can't compel anyone to stay with me,
但那... 简直是疯了 别去
but that's... that's mental. Don't do that.
我希望你三思
I wish you'd reconsider.
我没有选择
I wish I could.
我一直以为玛拉黛有越狱计划
Always assumed Maladie had a plan to escape.
但从没想过会是你
Never guessed it was you.
卡比女士去哪儿 我就...
Where Miss Carbey goes...
我会付你钱
I'll pay you.
-这是作弊  -那我很抱歉
- That's cheating! - Well, sorry!
没有你的帮助 我的计划还真行不通
Uh, my plan sort of doesn't work without you.
被需要的感觉真好
Nah, it's nice to be needed.
我们都得发表演讲吗
Do we all have to make a speech?
我知道我比你们大多数人都小
I know that I'm younger than most of you here,
但我觉得我有责任这么说
but I feel like it's my duty to say that
我很爱你们俩 并且...
I love you both very much, and...
我觉得我们应该什么都不做
I don't think anyone should do anything.
小心
Be careful.
艾菲・博伊尔
Effie Boyle.
"我的销量很重要"
"My sales matter."
她的销量会把人们变成一群暴徒
Her sales will turn this crowd into a mob.
是雨果・斯旺带她去见玛拉黛的吗
Do you think Hugo Swann got her in to see Maladie?
不... 没人帮她 这是她编的
No, no one got her in. This is fiction.
我真心以为她没这么下作
I honestly thought she was better than this.
我从没相信过她
I never trusted her, myself.
派个人把门 控制下进来的人数
Have the men keep a rough count of people coming in.
一到400人 就把大门关上
Get to 400, close the gates.
但有好几千人等着看呢
But there's thousands of people waiting.
那就把大门锁上
Then lock the gates.
法官只说公开处刑 没说要全市人看着
Judge said public, not packed.
放进来吧
Bring 'em in.
你们俩只是帮我们进去出来 没其他任务
You two are there to help us get in and out, nothing more.
乔治和维奥莱特
Um, George and Violet,
你们带着原型机回来
yous'll be back here with the prototype.
除了我 谁都别进入广场 直到...
No one goes into that square apart from me until...
我还以为你会去洞穴冒险
I thought you was going spelunking.
特鲁让我照顾你
True said take care of you.
好 那就更好了 来吧
Right. That'll make this easier, then. Come see.
"灵活杰克" 任务还是一样 只不过...
Nimble, it'll be the same, only...
嗯 我很乐意在上面
Yeah, I'm happy to stay up here.
我们得稍微练习一下
We're gonna need to practice this bit.
-让开  -注意点
- Hey, get off! - Oi, watch it!
国内最好的神枪手
Top marksmen in the country.
不到万不得已绝不开枪
They won't fire unless they have to.
但开枪了绝不失手
But they won't miss.
你怎么...
How did you, um...
地下世界那边谈的如何
How did you fare in the underworld?
乞丐王没什么兴趣
The king was unresponsive.
他说他的人没练过如何阻止斗争
He said his men weren't trained to stop fights.
可能无政府主义对他更有利
I suppose anarchy is a boon to him.
他的秘密生意就不会被发现
His dealings go unnoticed.
但我有告诉他哪些地区别插手
I did tell him which neighborhoods to stay out of.
你觉得我们该一劳永逸地解决他吗
Do you think we should deal with him more permanently?
乞丐王的宫廷政变
A beggar's palace coup?
以后再说吧
In time, perhaps.
人有点少
Crowd's a bit thin.
-斯旺  -派克因将军
- Swann. - Oh. General Pecking.
-吉尔伯特  -你也开始嗜血了 是吗
- Gilberto. - Developed a taste for blood, have you?
鲜血 是啊
Uh, blood, yes.
只要... 别是贵族的
Just, uh... not blue.
有事吗 先生
Can I help you, sir?
正好有点事
As it happens, you can.
我是你国外来的 最喜欢的叔叔
For I am your favorite uncle come from abroad,
-来看望你  -不可能
- just to see you. - Nah.
你是来看绞刑的 不是为了我
You're just here for the hanging. Not for me.
里面有桶金酒
Oh! We got a tub of gin inside.
汤姆 这是我叔叔
Tom, this is my uncle.
你好啊 汤姆
Hello, Tom!
记住 乔治 当你听到...
Remember, George, when you hear the...
两分钟长 然后放下手杆
It's two minutes, and then that lever goes down.
原型机布置好后
After the prototype's been deployed,
就开走 去...
you drive out, and you go to...
波吉尔路 鼓声后放下手杆
Porchill Road, after the drums, down.
阿尼尔和我是同学
Aneel and I studied together.
他知道我想做律师 但我们结婚时
He knows I mean to practice, but when we marry,
我得放弃我的爱好
I'm supposed to give up my hobby.
可我明明学得比他好
I'm a better student than he is.
就因为我学得比他好 他就要离开我
He's gonna leave me because I'm a better student than he is.
别傻了
Don't be daft.
我赌一英镑 他马上就拿着鲜花来道歉
A pound says he shows up with flowers and apologies
最晚明天
tomorrow at the latest.
没听到我让你们小声吗
Did you not hear my shushing?
-好了 安分点  -你
- All right, settle down! - Oi! You!
别推了 不然就给我出去
Stop pushing, or out you go!
这是个瓶子吗
Oi, is that a bottle?
给我 你还想怎么着...
Gimme that. You want something...
咋的 要哭啊 滚远点
What, you gonna cry? Fuck off.
-他心情不太好啊  -太好了
- He's in an uproar. - Thank goodness.
这样还省我功夫
It's less work for me.
6800千克的黄金
15,000 pounds of gold!
小声点 别让别人知道了
Shh, we do not tell the others.
-加油啊 小伙子们  -好的 叔叔
- Put your backs into it, lads. - Yes, uncle!
我爸爸从来都不看我的画
My dad never even looked at my paintings.
他说能当警察就够好了
He said a copper's life is good enough for me.
然后还拿走了我的刷子
Then he takes my brushes,
那他妈可是温莎牛顿 然后就...
Windsor and fucking Newton, no less, and...
[世界知名颜料品牌]
是玛拉黛
It's Maladie!
玛拉黛
Maladie!
别叫了 亲爱的 我马上就下去
Quit yelling, love. I'll be down in a minute.
好好让恶魔付出代价
You give the devil what for!
-你个该死的禽兽  -他们应该烧死你
- You're a fuckin' animal! - They should burn you!
快啊 吊死那婊子
Go on, then! Drop the bitch!
吊死那婊子
Go on! Drop her! Drop the bitch!
Drop the bitch! Drop the bitch!
吊死那婊子
Drop the bitch!
Drop the bitch! Drop the bitch!
吊死那婊子
Drop the bitch!
-小心  -我去 够重的
- Careful. - Oh, blimey, this is heavy.
背好痛
My back is killing me.
你个该死的禽兽
You're a fucking animal!
吊死那婊子
Drop the bitch! Drop the bitch!
开枪 守卫开枪啊
Shoot! Shoot, guards!
她不想被救
She didn't want to be rescued.
不
No.
她想让人看到
She wanted people to see.
观众
An audience.
她要杀了我们
She's gonna kill us.
所有来见证她死亡的人
Everyone who came to see her die.
-快离开  -等等
- Get out! - Wait.
-你必须得...  -闭嘴
- No, you have to get... - No, just shut up.
我们脚下的电线是干什么的
What are these power lines under us?
这不是连通监狱的
They don't go to the prison.
那些围栏是金属的吗
Are those barricades metal?
这是我的荣幸
It's been a privilege.
离开围栏
Away from the railings!
博奇 让他们离开围栏
Birch! Get 'em off the railings!
推开他们 推开
Get 'em off the railings! Get 'em off!
让开
Move! Move!
后退
Move back!
这是怎么回事
What the hell's happening?
狗日的电力
Fucking electricity.
快逃 快
Move out. Out.
所有人... 都出去
Ev... Everyone... Everyone out.
乔治 别启动
George, don't deploy!
别碰手杆
Don't touch the lever!
他们活该死得更惨
They deserve worse.
开门 这边
Open it! This way!
过来
Oi. Come here.
不 不 不
No! No, no, no. No, don't!
特鲁让我照顾你
True said take care of you.
哈莉特 哈莉特
Oh! Harriet! Harriet!
我去找人帮你
I'll, I'll get help!
我马上回来
I'll be back!
快点 这边 快
Come on, come on! Go, go!
天啊 哈莉特
Oh, God, Harriet!
消灭附魔之人
No more Touched! No more Touched!
这边
Over there.
带她过来
Bring her in.
你那边如何
Go all right?
把她腿抬起来
Put her feet up.
你呢
You?
暴乱
Uh, it was a riot.
我只杀天使
I only kill angels.
她说那个警探既聪明又诚实
She talked about the detective who was smart,
他很悲伤 所以她没嫁给他
and honest, and she didn't marry him because he was sad.
我的销量很重要
My sales matter.
她的销量会把人们变成一群暴徒
Her sales will turn this crowd into a mob.
在职业女性中很受欢迎
It's popular with working women.
手指沾点墨并不代表你是记者 博伊尔
Inky fingers don't make you a reporter, Boyle.
看到这些刺伤了吗
You see the stab wounds?
-你当时在那  -这是谁
- You were there. - Who's this?
谋杀
Murder.
别傻了
Don't be stupid!
这边
This way!